

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT · CLOUD ARCHITECT

206, Chuo 4-58-10, Nakano-ku, Tokyo, 164-0011, Japan

🛘 (+81) 70-4486-7966 | 🗷 pinakpani.m95@gmail.com | 🖸 pinakpani-mukherjee | 🗖 pinakpani-mukherjee-61573b166 | 👽 pinakpanimukherjee.com

"Acta Non Verba."

Summary

Currently a consultant at Terdata Japan, working as a cloud architecture specialist for our internal products. Experience with creating POCs(Proof of Concepts) of our products including Teradata Vantage, etc. for our clients in the cloud and migrating their current on-prem data to the cloud as well. Experience in working as a Data Engineer for a Japanese Unicorn bought out by Paypal(Paidy) with a focus on creating pipelines using a DAG based software(Prefect) and distributed computing using Apache Spark. Am a developer in my free time, working on my personal apps on iOS and a fan of the Rust Programming Language. Was a recipient of the MEXT(Monbukagakusho) Scholarship through the recommendation of the Embassy of Japan in India.

Work Experience _____

Teradata Japan Tokyo, Japan

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

Jun. 2023 - Current

Feb. 2021 - May. 2023

- Engaged with clients in the Network and Automobile industries to understand their current data warehousing goals and challenges.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including data scientists, engineers, and analysts, to design and architect innovative solutions for our clients.
- · Focused on improving documentation for our clients for future requests, and maintenance after implementation.
- Created POCs(Proof of Concepts) for our solutions in the cloud, both AWS and GCP. Including setting up and architecting the entire infrastructure for our On-Prem clients.
- · Migrated On-Prem services to the cloud in a timely fashion, while adhering to best practices for data migration.

Paidy Tokyo, Japan

DATA ENGINEER

- · Worked on fraud detection and real time analysis of purchases made through our services.
- Created and managed ETL jobs and pipelines to satisfy business needs of our internal users.
 Worked with data engineering best principles within the data pipeline through AWS, Kafka and Elastic Search.
- Maintained legacy software crucial to Fraud Detection.
- Created and maintained of internal data-science and data-engineering tooling.
- Focused on proper data sanitation and data architecture. For eg. implementation of the Medallion Architecture on all new data sources in Paidy.

Certificates & Awards

CERTIFICATES

2023	Associate Cloud Engineer, Google Cloud Services	Japan
2023	Professional Cloud Architect, Google Cloud Services	Japan
2023	Solutions Architect, Associate, Amazon Web Services	Japan
2023	Cloud Practitioner, Foundational, Amazon Web Services	Japan

AWARDS

2017 MEXT Scholarship, Embassy Recommendation, MEXT Japan

Japan

Education

Yokohama National University

Yokohama, Japan

B.Eng. in Electronics and Computer Science

Apr. 2018 - Feb. 2023

· Graduated with a Bachelors in Electronics and Computer Sciences. Research focused on radars and Machine Learning.

Tokyo University of Foreign Languages

Tokyo, Japan

DIPLOMA IN JAPANESE LANGUAGE

Apr. 2017 - Feb. 2018

Graduated with a degree in Japanese under the direction and supervision of the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology(MEXT)

Extracurricular Activity

Languages

GENERAL

Native: English, BengaliFluent: Japanese, Hindi

Languages

PROGRAMMING

Expert: Python, JavaScript, ScalaIntermediate: Swift, Go, Java

• Basic: C, C++

Technologies

SOFTWARE

- ML: PyTorch, Tensorflow
- · SQL Databases: Postgres, MYSQL
- NO-SQL Databases: Cassandra, MongoDB, DocumentDB, ElasticSearch, Redis
- Distributed Systems: Apache Spark
- Operations: Apache Kafka, Amazon MSK, Apache Airflow, Prefect
- Data Warehousing: Amazon Redshift, Teradata Vantage
- Backend Design: FastAPI,Gin(Golang)
- Frontend Design: Next.JS

Sports & Passions

GENERAL

- Wrestling
- Judo
- Brazilian Jiu Jitsu
- Photography
- Piano

Professional & Soft Skills

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Teradata **Project Management**, Training to become a Project Manager within my Organization.

Paidy **Open Source Software**, Experience with Apache Spark, Airflow.

Paidy Dataflow Automation, Experience with Prefect.

Paidy Cloud ML Services, Experience with AWS Sagemaker to perform ML services on User data.

SOFT SKILLS

External **People Management**, Experience in delegating jobs and workflows to teammates

External **Organization**, Ability to Organize and Plan well for the project without much supervision.

Self **Communication**, Ability to translate Technical Jargon to non technical people in an efficient manner.

Self Motivation, Ability to pick and work on required topics in a self directed way without much supervision.